Gian Carlo Torres

Full Stack Software Developer

geanu@outlook.com | +14083689565 | Brooklyn, NY | geanu.netlify.app | linkedin.com/in/geanu

SUMMARY

8+ years of experience in computer programming space, recently gained proficiency in modern frameworks and programming concepts such as Full-Stack Software Engineering with React.ts and Flask, and Mobile Application development with React Native. Recently collaborated with a product team to develop an MVP for ExpenseBuddy over 8 weeks. Currently in an apprenticeship with TechFleet, looking for new challenges in Software Engineering.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

<u>Frontend:</u> React.js, React.ts, JavaScript, TypeScript, TailwindCSS, Bootstrap, Styled-Components, CSS3, HTML5 <u>Backend</u>: Python, Flask, Node.js, REST API, Postgres, SQLAlchemy

<u>Tools & Apps</u>: Vite, NPM, VS Code, Figma (Locofy, Anima & Rendition), Trello, Insomnia, Notion, Jupyter Notebook, Github, AWS <u>Principles & Techniques</u>: Reusable Components, Hooks, Responsive Design, OOP, SDLC, CI/CD, Cloud Architecture

<u>Certificates</u>: <u>Software Developer Certificate</u>, <u>Full-Stack Software Engineering Certificate</u>, <u>Mobile Applications Development (React Native) Certificate</u>, <u>Solutions Architect Associate Certificate</u>, <u>Data Analyst in Python Certificate</u>, <u>Data Engineering Certificate</u>

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

ExpenseBuddy [Home] [App] [Github] (2023)

- A user-friendly web app, powered by technologies including Vite, React, and Flask, designed to simplify the task of recording and managing business-related travel and vehicle expenses for self-employed individuals and business owners.
- Built the frontend using React.js and Styled-Components and backend using Flask, Python and Postgres.
- Followed the design on Figma and organized ticketing tasks using Trello.

Brekky [Home] - Frontend [App] [Github] - Backend [App] [Github] (2023)

- A social media platform for people who are passionate about cooking and enables them to add their spin on recipes found all
 over the world!
- Built the frontend using React, TypeScript, Tailwind and React Hook Forms, while the backend using Flask, Python, Postgres, SQLAlchemy and Marshmallow for APIs.
- Web application communication and CRUD methods using APIs. Deployed frontend on Netlify, backend on Render, database on ElephantSQL and enabled CI/CD through Github. Utilized themealsdb API.

EDUCATION

Co.Lab - Software Developer

- Collaborated across disciplines in an 8-week learning program, contributing as a software developer in a product team.
- Conducted research, documenting technical feasibility, and identifying constraints to inform decision-making processes.
- Translated design concepts into actionable tasks, breaking down wireframes into detailed, executable technical requirements.
- Demonstrated proficiency in implementing Figma designs with a focus on building high-priority features and resolving bugs.
- Actively participated in agile development processes, ensuring seamless communication between team members.

Coding Temple - Software Engineering Trainee

2023

2023

- Completed the full-stack software engineering program, focusing on building to deployment of modern web applications.
- Deployed a capstone project utilizing React TypeScript/JavaScript on the frontend and Flask Python/Postgres on the backend.
- Proficiency in JavaScript and Python, with best programming practices in DRY, data structure complexity and algorithms.

De La Salle - College of Saint Benilde, Manila

Information Systems, Bachelor of Science

2007 - 2010

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer Apprentice, Tech Fleet (Remote)

2023 - present

 Collaborating with cross-functional teams, including product designers and backend developers, to ensure a cohesive on-boarding flow that aligns with overall product goals.

Computer Systems Analyst, SAE Engineering, Inc. (Santa Clara, CA)

2012 - 2020

- Initiated planning and strategy for transition and migration of legacy processes into the ERP system, mainly for Operations, Purchasing, Sales and Accounting departments.
- Designed use case and data flow models for business process development, and conduct project modular demonstrations, development timetables, implementation process and training.
- Managed the legacy database to Job Boss ERP, report writing, data migration, systems integration and training that made the
 ease of data access to generate modular reports.